<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="changelog_text" translatable="false"><![CDATA[
        <p>
            <h3>Version 1.22.0</h3>
            <b>Shortcut Placement / Using in Other Apps</b><br>
            You may have encountered a problem when trying to use shortcuts in other apps (e.g. Tasker), where it would not select or make the other app crash. There is now an alternative method of selecting a shortcut that you may try in this case. Simply retry selecting the shortcut and you will be prompted with a dialog that asks you to pick either the new or the old method.
            <br><br>
            <b>Longer Timeouts</b><br>
            It is now possible to have request timeouts of up to 10 minutes.
            <br><br>
            <b>Bugfixes</b>
            <ul>
                <li>Request body of <i>multipart/form</i> requests now currently uses CRLF instead of only LF</li>
                <li>Fixed various rare app crashes</li>
            </ul>
        </p>
        <p>
            <h3>Version 1.21.0</h3>
            <b>Shortcut Actions</b><br>
            You can now define what happens before and after a shortcut is executed. This includes things like displaying a Toast message, extracting part of the response or triggering another shortcut. More to come in future updates!
            <br><br>
            <b>Support for multipart/form-data</b><br>
            In addition to sending a custom request body and simple parameters, it is now also possible to send form data, i.e, using the "multipart/form-data" content type.
            <br><br>
            <b>Miscellaneous</b>
            <ul>
                <li>New translations: Norwegian (Bokmål), Italian</li>
                <li>Shortcut can be opened in browser</li>
                <li>Improved syntax highlighting & pretty printing of JSON & XML responses</li>
            </ul>
            <b>Bugfixes</b>
            <ul>
                <li>Delayed execution & waiting for network connectivity now work again</li>
                <li>Custom icons now show on the home screen on Oreo</li>
                <li>gzipped responses are now correctly parsed</li>
                <li>Various occasional crashes</li>
            </ul>
        </p>
        <br>
        <p>
            <h3>Version 1.20.0</h3>
            <b>Simplified Variable Insertion</b><br>
            Inserting variables into shortcuts has now become much easier. Each input field that supports variables now has a button next to it. Clicking it opens a popup dialog with a list of all available variables, allowing you to easily pick and insert one.
            <br><br>
            <b>Improved Tasker Integration</b><br>
            When triggering shortcuts from Tasker, it is now possible to send along variables. Simply define variables with the same name in Tasker as in your shortcut and their value will automatically be sent from Tasker to your shortcut when triggered.
            <br><br>
            <b>Drag & Drop Reordering</b><br>
            Categories & Variables, as well as options of <i>select</i> & <i>toggle</i> variables, can now easily be reordered via drag & drop.
            <br><br>
            <b>Improved Specification of Request Body</b><br>
            When specifying the request body of a shortcut, you now have the option to chose between <i>x-www-form-urlencoded</i>, i.e., the body is a list of parameters, or <i>custom text</i>, i.e., you specify the request body as raw text and give it a content-type.
            <br><br>
            <b>Variables within Variables!</b><br>
            The <i>constant</i>, <i>toggle</i> and <i>select</i> variable types now support recursive resolution of values. This means you can reference other variables from these variables. For example, you could set up a <i>select</i> variable where one of the options is a <i>color</i> variable.
            <br><br>
            <b>Miscellaneous</b>
            <ul>
                <li>The input field for request parameter values now allows multiline input.</li>
                <li>The cURL export dialog now includes a <i>copy</i> button to allow you to quickly copy the cURL command to the clipboard.</li>
                <li>The <i>About</i> section in the settings now features a <i>Translate this App</i> button as a call-to-action for translators. Help me translate everything!</li>
            </ul>
        </p>
        <br>
        <p>
            <h3>Version 1.19.0</h3>
            - New variable type: number slider<br>
            - "Number Input" variable allows decimals and minus sign<br>
            - Better support for user-defined certificates<br>
            - Password input is hidden<br>
            - Internal storage is encrypted
        </p>
        <p>
            <h3>Version 1.18.0</h3>
            - French translations<br>
            - Fixed shortcut creation on Oreo<br>
            - Added Privacy Policy & Crash Reporting opt-out<br>
            - Minor bugfixes
        </p>
        <p>
            <h3>Version1.17.0</h3>
            - New variable types: date & time<br>
            - Fixed/improved retry on failure<br>
            - Option to delay shortcut execution<br>
            - Portuguese translations<br>
            - Improved quality of custom icons<br>
            - Minor bugfixes
        </p>
        <p>
            <h3>Version1.16.0</h3>
            - Support for Digest Auth<br>
            - Support for OPTIONS, HEAD and TRACE methods<br>
            - Launcher Shortcuts (Android 7.1 and up only)<br>
            - Categories can have different layout types: list or grid<br>
            - Minor bugfixes & other improvements
        </p>
        <p>
            <h3>Version1.15.0</h3>
            - Shortcuts can be exported as cURL commands<br>
            - Chinese translations<br>
            - Minor bugfixes
        </p>
        <p>
            <h3>Version1.14.0</h3>
            - Syntax highlighting for JSON and XML responses<br>
            - Import shortcuts from cURL commands<br>
            - Improved import &amp; export<br>
            - Themes<br>
            - Minor bugfixes
        </p>
        <p>
            <h3>Version1.13.0</h3>
            - New variable type: color<br>
            - Allow sharing text snippets into variables<br>
            - New app icon
        </p>
        <p>
            <h3>Version1.12.0</h3>
            - New response options: show in dialog or window<br>
            - Option to remember/forget variable values<br>
            - Pending executions can be cancelled
        </p>
    	<p>
			<h3>Version1.11.0</h3>
			- Variables: inject custom values through prompt dialogs<br>
			- Plugin support for integration with automation apps (e.g. Tasker)
	    </p>
        <p>
			<h3>Version1.10.1</h3>
			- Shortcuts are removed from homescreen when deleted in app<br>
			- Fixed a crash when saving shortcuts
	    </p>
        <p>
			<h3>Version1.10.0</h3>
			- Shortcuts can be organized into categories<br>
			- Possibility to accept any certificate<br>
			- More icons<br>
			- <i>Acknowledgements</i> section in settings screen<br>
			- Bugfixes
	    </p>
        <p>
            <h3>Version1.9.2</h3>
            - Bugfixes
        </p>
        <p>
			<h3>Version1.9.1</h3>
			- Layout improvements<br>
			- Auto-complete suggestions for custom headers<br>
			- Import/Export uses JSON format now<br>
			- Improved execution retries after reconnecting with the internet<br>
			- Bugfixes
		</p>
        <p>
			<h3>Version1.8.0</h3>
			- Shortcut execution can be delayed when not connected to the internet<br>
			- Added <i>View in Play Store</i> button to settings screen
		</p>
		<p>
			<h3>Version1.7.0</h3>
			- Shortcuts can have different timeouts (3, 10, 30 or 60 seconds)<br>
			- Added <i>About</i> section to settings screen<br>
			- Added <i>What\'s new</i> dialog<br>
			- Minor language improvements
		</p>
		<p>
			<h3>Version1.6.1</h3>
			- Bugfixes
		</p>
		<p>
			<h3>Version1.6.0</h3>
			- Custom headers<br>
			- Custom request body<br>
			- Settings Screen<br>
			- Import & Export (new permissions needed)<br>
			- New request methods: <i>PUT</i>, <i>DELETE</i>, <i>PATCH</i><br>
			- Shortcuts can be tested before being saved<br>
			- Bugfixes
		</p>
		<p>
			<h3>Version1.5.0</h3>
			- Possibility to add <i>POST</i> parameters<br>
			- More built-in icons, with improved selector dialog
		</p>
		<p>
			<h3>Version1.4.0</h3>
			- Built-in icons<br>
			- Shortcuts can have descriptions for the overview screen<br>
			- Bugfix: Connections are no longer left idle after use
		</p>
		<p>
			<h3>Version1.2.0</h3>
			- Added support for Ipack icons
		</p>
		<p>
			<h3>Version1.1.0</h3>
			- Shortcuts can be moved up and down in the shortcut list<br>
			- Default click action executes the shortcuts instead of opening context menu<br>
			- Buttons moved into action bar<br>
			- Bugfixes
		</p>
]]></string>
    <string name="help_variables" translatable="false"><![CDATA[
        <p>
            <b>What are variables?</b><br>
            Variables allow you to inject pieces of information dynamically into your shortcuts when executing them. A variable consists of a key and a value which is resolved at execution time, based on its type. For some variable types this means that a prompt dialog is shown that asks for a value, others can be resolved without user input.
        </p>
        <p>
            <b>How do I use variables?</b><br>
            You can insert a placeholder for a variable into your shortcuts\' url, requests parameters, request body, authentication and header fields by clicking the \"{ }\" button next to the input field and selecting a variable.
        </p>
        <p>
            When executing a shortcut that contains variable placeholders all of them are resolved according to their type.
        </p>
        <p>
            You can also insert these placeholders into some of your variables, i.e., you can have variables reference other variables.
        </p>
        <p>
            <b>What are the different types of variables?</b><br>
            There are 10 different types of variables:</p>
        <p>
            <u>Constant</u><br>
            A <i>constant</i> stores a value, until explicitly changed. There is no prompt dialog. It can be used to store a piece of information that is shared across multiple shortcut, such as an authentication token or a domain name. This way it can easily be changed.<br>
            There are also certain actions that can be attached to a shortcut that allow you to change the value of a constant, e.g., by storing part of the HTTP response into it.
        </p>
        <p>
            <u>Toggle</u><br>
            The <i>toggle</i> type consists of a list of values. There is no prompt dialog. Every time it is used it resolves to the next value in the list. When the last value is reached it starts again from the first.
        </p>
        <p>
            <u>Selection</u><br>
            The <i>selection</i> type consists of a list of options, each of which has a value and a label. It triggers a dialog from which one of the options can be selected.
        </p>
        <p>
            <u>Text, Number and Password</u><br>
            The <i>text</i>, <i>number</i> and <i>password</i> types trigger a prompt dialog where a value can be entered into a text field.
        </p>
        <p>
            <u>Number Slider</u><br>
            The <i>number slider</i> type is similar to the <i>number</i>. It allows you to pick a number. However, the number is entered using a horizontal slider, for which you can define the minimum and maximum value, as well as the step size.
        </p>
        <p>
            <u>Date and Time</u><br>
            The <i>date</i> and <i>time</i> types trigger a prompt dialog where a date or time can be selected. The output format can be specified according to Android\'s <a href="https://developer.android.com/reference/java/text/SimpleDateFormat.html">SimpleDateFormat</a>.
        </p>
        <p>
            <u>Color</u><br>
            The <i>color</i> type triggers a prompt dialog where a color can be selected. Its value is returned in RGB hex format (e.g. ff0000 for red).
        </p>
        <p>
            <b>What does <i>Allow \'Share …\'</i> mean?</b><br><b>How can I share text into variables?</b><br>
            In the advanced settings section of a variable you can mark it as <i>Allow \'Share …\'</i>. This makes it possible to provide the value of this variable through Android\'s <i>Share</i>-dialog, e.g. by sharing a URL or text snippet from another app. The variable will then assume the shared value during execution.
        </p>
    ]]></string>
    <string name="privacy_policy" translatable="false"><![CDATA[
        <p>
            <b>General</b><br>
            All data entered into the app is only ever sent to the domains specified by the user through the use of shortcuts. No data about the user, their behavior or device is ever collected or sent to the developer or any other third-party as part of this app.<br><br>The only exception to this is crash reporting (see below).
        </p>
        <p><b>Crash Reporting</b><br>
            The app uses the third-party library Bugsnag to collect crash reports. This serves the purpose of discovering and fixing bugs in the app. The collected data contains basic information about the device and the type of crash. No personal information such as usernames, email addresses or IP addresses is collected.<br><br>The user has the option to opt-out of the sending of these crash reports.
        </p>
    ]]></string>
</resources>
